The challenge that I think a lot of the
industry has right now is there isn't an
agreed upon standard for storing in git
history like well this written by AI or
noting. And at a high level what we've
seen is engineers are generating or are
changing about 70% more lines of code
per week than what we saw at the end of
2023. So we think a lot of that should
largely be attributable to AI.
>> So in this context now you can interact
with the LLMs through graphite. You can
interact with the graphite agent to edit
the code within the PR. And you've sort
of seen a bunch of Claude and others
introduce maybe review elements and
you're kind of encroaching into that
space. How do you see the boundaries or
the right scope of a product?
>> I could see a world where graph isn't
necessarily like building a firstparty
review agent. Our goal is very much to
be like the interface layer and like the
best place to interact with and control
many different agents you working on
your code changes. I also think then
there's another opportunity to be the
control plane for all of those agents
and that is really where I think we see
the most opportunity.
>> If AI is doing the review, I think I
would want to consume that review as
part of my ongoing development as
opposed to wait until I publish a PR.
Why do I need to wait until I open the
pull request?
>> Yeah, that's a great question.
[Music]
Hello everyone. Welcome back to the AI
native dev. Thanks for tuning back in.
Today we're going to review everything
about review and code review. And to dig
into that, we have the CEO and
co-founder of Graphite, uh, Mary
Llutzki. Merryill, thanks for coming on
and joining us here on the show.
>> Thanks for having me, guy.
>> Um, so let me say a couple of words
about Graphite and do kind of keep me
honest here if I misrepresent. So your
and you've been around a bunch of years.
Uh your kind of core innovation has been
on code review, but like human code
review before, right? You had this uh
smart insight and great tooling that
allowed these sort of stacked PRs where
you can create a snippet of your work
and start sharing it and get reviews as
you build those out. And that's that's
been great. You know, my team here at
Tesla has been using it, you know,
loving it. Uh and that was kind of a
great invasion. Then AI came along. uh
and you've been leaning much more
heavily into AI code review now and your
reviewer there uh Diamond and so uh
let's maybe start from just uh
understanding a little bit more about
what it is that uh that you do in that
sort of AI code review.
>> From the beginning we've been focused on
the problem of code review and um how we
unblock um the outer loop and kind of
the second half of the story of what
happens once a PR is ready like finished
and and you know complete or ready to to
be reviewed. there's still so much work
that needs to happen to get that from
you know from like that first that first
draft of the PR out to production and uh
we started you know we started from
taking inspiration from companies like
Google and meta that have built amazing
internal tooling um and great workflows
to help tens of thousands of engineers
coordinate uh across different time
zones and uh be able to ship as quickly
as as those companies do. Um so from the
beginning we we were focused on how do
we unblock the outer loop like
accelerate code review. Um taking more
of like a workflow and and tooling
approach to that. Um stack PRs was the
the main innovation that we we were
borrowing there. Um basically the idea
is like how do we break down big changes
and you know let you review and like put
pre changes up for review u and then
keep developing on top of them um while
you do that. So you've kind of decoupled
the review uh like review and
development processes and let those go
on in parallel. So the first chapter of
graphite was really like bringing that
to every company on top of GitHub. Then
I think you know you had you know a year
and a half ago you had sonnet 3.5
released all of a sudden everything
changes as far as how software is built
and every team is adopting cursor and
cloud code and these amazing tools and I
I think it both made the problem that we
were working on 10 times more important
um and it gave us an incredible tool to
go and solve it with AI. So, um, you
know, the problem is 10 times more
important because they're now 10 times
more PRs in some cases. Like every
engineer has a has a bunch of cloud code
windows open working simultaneously.
Like you're able to build Yeah. you're
able to build features like so much
faster than than ever before. Uh, but
the result of that is is that you just
have a mountain of PRs piling up waiting
for review. And uh we hear from a lot of
our our customers that you know many of
their most senior engineers are now just
buried in like mountains of PRs from
more you from junior folks that are just
turning these out um with you know with
AI tooling now. So uh we knew we wanted
to solve like our existing tooling u
like helps teams solve that. We also
knew that we needed to do more. So um we
created uh graphite agent u formerly
called diamond uh which is our AI
reviewer. Uh the the idea there was like
can we can we take you a lot of the work
that a human reviewer would do and just
like hand that to AI um have it catch
like many of the bugs and you know nits
and style inconsistencies um you know
follow custom rules find security
vulnerabilities like can it do that
first pass uh of at code review and kind
of shortcut that so that you know as an
author of a PR you get feedback in a few
seconds and then by the time you loop in
a human colleague like there's still a
human in the loop checking that, but you
know, fundamentally, you know, they're
able to then look at for like higher
order problems and not have to spend as
much time like nitpicking and reading
every single line of code necessarily.
And that's exactly what we've done uh
like graphite agent. Now, many of our
our top customers now have, you know,
have expanded to use graphite agent. I
think the big change that we've made
there is now bringing the chat
functionality into the graphite PR page.
So you can actually now collaborate with
graphite agent um live on the pull
request from graphite. You can have it
you can have it like update things for
you. Um you can ask it questions. Um it
can go into your codebase and search for
relevant context. Like it's much more of
now making it you making the PR a
collaborative experience rather than you
rather than just a point of validation.
And I think that's super interesting for
you know for working with AI. So as you
review and as you kind of build in and
you introduce this code reviewer, I'm
curious first just sort of understand a
little bit more about the substance of
what it does and doesn't review well. So
I guess what are the types of problems
you've seen it most successful uh
dealing with and maybe the other way
around like what are what are the gaps
where you say well at the moment I'm
sure it gets better over time but at the
moment uh it is its boundaries its
capabilities boundaries. I think the the
things that it's really good at um it's
great at finding bugs and like logic any
logic errors. Uh it's very good. I think
there's also interestingly we've seen
there's a class of bug where u it can be
it's hard for a human to spot or where
you know the the type checker wouldn't
find it u where just like looking at it
with your eyes you wouldn't necessarily
spot it immediately. And I think you
know AI on the other hand is very good
at finding at like you know finding
those type of bugs and calling those
out. So we've seen that as like an
interesting uh interesting class of of
issues that that is particularly good at
finding. Um it's very good at style like
style guide adherence. Um it's good at
finding security vulnerabilities. is um
it can pretty much do most of what uh
what like a human reviewer can do at
least at like that uh that like first
level of of review like looking at
looking at the diff itself. A couple
things that it's it's not great at yet.
Um one is like higher level architecture
decisions like I think that's still very
much in the realm of like you need you
know you need to have like a senior
engineer who's who's thinking about the
entire system. Uh, I don't think we yet
have, it's getting better certainly, but
it's still I don't think we yet have
like the context to to be able to do
that. Um the other piece I'd say is uh I
think there's a really interesting
opportunity and something we're actively
exploring is uh can we validate that
this change is actually doing what it
was what it's supposed to like end to
end and is that the agent is spinning
this up on you know on a box and u
clicking through it and and recording a
video and adding that to the change u
you know something like that I think is
is an interesting direction for you know
for this to go and u then I'd say the
other piece that's that's a little more
difficult right now is uh there's some
languages that just aren't really well
represented in in AI training sets and
um those end up being things that are
more esoteric end up being like a bit
more difficult for for the reviewer to
get right. Um for some reason it's like
it's bad it's bad at cotlin right now.
We don't know why exactly but we're
that's something we we keep getting
whenever we're in mobile repos we see
that a lot. So it sounds like the the
challenges are mostly on either sort of
LLM limitations of you know the brain is
still not good enough uh around it and
on I guess kind of breadth of context
like when you think about architecture
or end to end testing for sure but with
the architecture would you say that
today's limits are more around kind of
the reasoning capabilities like you can
you can give it all the information
about all that context and it's just
kind of not smart enough yet to to
extract that out or or is it or is it
more of a product problem still of I
just need like bring all the relevant
information uh to the hands of the LLM
but the intelligence is already there.
>> I think it's more the latter where so
much of this like I think the reasoning
is is there if you give it perfect
information but the challenge is that a
lot of the considerations that go into
like good architecture are you know from
so many like disperate sources of
context. that might be you know in one
engineer's head who built the system 2
years ago like u it might be in a notion
doc that's you know that's been lying
dormant for a long time like there's so
there's so many places where this is is
kind of fanned out in an organization
and um you know tribal knowledge that it
is I think I think this is one of the
great one of the things that that we're
we're working on is like how do we bring
all of those pieces of context and like
provenence for a change into the PR you
know more so than than ever before and
provide the agent with enough enough
context to actually actually like think
through the problem at at that scale.
And but I I do think that we're we're
close if not there already as far as the
the capabilities of the model themselves
um given given the right information.
>> Yeah, that's interesting. Although it is
interesting to think about whether the
training data connecting these two kind
of gaps, the training data for what is
good architecture is probably also kind
of a bit more limited.
>> Fair there. So as you look at this, you
know, you've sort of had a stretch, you
still do, sort of see a bunch of human
code uh and reviews uh and now you're
seeing a bunch of AI. So I guess kind of
two related questions. One is can you
tell the two apart? I mean, does the
system track those? I don't know if you
have any sort of stats or sort of data
around it, but in general perception
around, you know, the amount of AI code
coming in and importantly like uh are
there like types of mistakes or sort of
problems that you think are more kind of
AI prevalent than human prevalent? This
is a challenge that I think a lot of the
industry has right now is that there's
there isn't an agreed upon standard for
you know for like you know storing in in
git history like what was was this
written by by AI or not. I think there's
something that'd be something that'd be
very interesting and at a high level
what we've seen is uh engineers are are
generating or are are changing about 70%
more lines of code per week uh than what
we saw at the end of 2023. So, uh, we
think a lot of that is largely, you
know, will should largely be
attributable to AI. Um, you know, GitHub
has published stats in the past about
like, you know, over half of the code on
on GitHub now being AI generated. I'm
sure it's it's probably closer to like,
you know, 2/3 to to 3/4 at this point.
Um, given the trend, I don't think we we
hit Daario's like 90% by September
projection, but I think it's the path to
that I think is is fairly clear. So, um,
we're seeing a lot more AI generated
code. there's no st there's no way to
really tell it apart at the moment
especially for organizations with top
tier engineering talent like the quality
does tend to be like lower than the the
median engineer there
>> yeah yeah yeah exactly I think that
that's there's some organizations it's
interesting because I think there's some
organizations for which u for AI is now
like better than the median engineer and
and I think for for many of our
customers though like that's not that's
like decidedly not the case yet and uh
there's still like very much a need for
you know for us to like refine to check
and refine particularly AIE code.
>> You you mentioned that it adheres to
style guides and the likes. Uh I'd love
to talk a little bit about what is the
source of truth that you kind of
contrast the reviews uh against you know
where what has been sort of effective in
terms of of defining kind of correctness
and quality uh and what's the experience
for someone to to input this you know
who is it that is uh that is entering
this uh this gospel. Yeah. So, we've
we've put a lot into uh into letting
customers customize uh customize the
reviewer, add their own rules. It's like
so much of code review is this this kind
of store of institutional knowledge and
and style and uh we have so with with
graphite agent you can define you can
define custom rules either um in English
um or you you can give it you can give
it like reax that you wanted to look for
around this like helping it you helping
it to to like focus on particular types
of of issues we have more common do
people like the regex more because it's
controlled or do they like the sort of
the uh English. Yeah, they like they
like conventional the conventional
language. Uh we also will ingest uh
we'll look for if there's like a you
know if there's like a claw MD or like
you know cursor rules file um we'll
ingest that and add that to to context
as well just so that there's there's
consistency there. Uh this is another
place where I think there's a lot of
different a lot of like you know
different standards that are are
evolving and uh you know we we basically
just try to like vacuum up as many of
them as we have to add another one to uh
to roll
we'll say actually in the comment uh
like if it was attributable to a
particular rule and uh we show insights
as well in the product of like which
which rules are are triggering the most
and uh like what we're what we're
catching and and what we're not. So um
we try to have like a good feedback loop
there of of things that we yeah of like
customization and then seeing the impact
of of that in terms of the the AI
reviews. whose job is it to enter this
data like things like uh the claud that
you read from a repo for instance know
that is the repo's information and
presumably the appdev team that is
working on that it's building but maybe
the definition of what high quality code
is or what secure code is and all that
that is more some platform team's
responsibility of it is who who
configures the the rules or or the the
languages in uh in graphite
>> it's usually like a developer
productivity or developer developer
infra team, they're usually the ones who
are admins on the GitHub repo. They're
configuring graphite more generally for
for the organization. So, at at a large
company like Shopify, you know, we'll
work really closely with with that Dev
Infra team and uh you know, make sure
that we're that we're pulling in the
right sources of context and, you know,
setting them you setting up the the
right knowledge there. Um, for smaller
teams though, you know, it's much like
on on GitHub, like it's kind of a
free-for-all, like anybody can, you
know, many of them will will set it so
that like anybody can add a rule and
anyone can update it. Uh, which I think
there's like something nice about that
where, you know, you just get you get
like as many as many inputs as possible
and like you can kind of like converge
on uh on like the right set of rules
much quicker. But obviously for large
organizations um it makes more sense to
centralize it and we want to support
that as well. So, you know, you're not
alone in introducing a a a reviewer and
specifically a poll request reviewer,
but clearly you've been around before.
Um, I I would kind of posit that
Graphite's original success was very
much around user experience. You know,
it was a methodology and kind of an ease
and you kind of nailed some of that sort
of developer zeitgeist uh of uh this is
an elegant way of working in a way that
I guess we've come to appreciate that
it's it's hard to get simple things
right. uh and and build those out. Now,
in the AI code review, there's a certain
sense that, you know, everything that
you've described, if I was to kind of
bring along, you know, many many other
sort of code review uh builders, uh
there will probably be a lot of
repetition. What what do you think,
>> yes,
>> makes a company stand out in this space?
You know, what makes it, you know, not
just a um whatever to use the sort of
the cliche lingo of it, just sort of a
rapper on top of the LLM. Yeah, I think
that there's I mean I think that there
there's obviously a lot of interest in
in the space right now like you know
we're certainly not the only ones who
have recognized that the volume of AI
generated code is means that there will
be a massive opportunity to like help
teams like review it faster. I think the
thing that the thing that differentiates
us and and what we what we believe is
graphites graphite's like core advantage
in the space is that uh we span the
entire life cycle of the pull request.
It's not just a bot that that plugs into
GitHub and comments in this one this one
part of the life cycle. we're able to
go, you know, all the way from the
moment the PR is created of like, you
know, enhancing that with like you
describing the change, you know,
generating a description for it, uh,
pulling in the right reviewers, doing
the AI review certainly, but then
helping the author iterate on that,
helping reviewers like, you know,
understand the change better and, um,
walking reviewers through that on, you
know, on the as part of their review,
helping to solve CI failures as they
come up. um and prompting just like
prompting the author to you to accept
the change and rerun it. Um solving
merge conflicts like I think the the
view you know and we're not quite there
yet but I think the view of of graphite
agent is that it really should be this
you almost this like companion that's
that's helping to shepherd your changes
through all the different steps of the
process. I'd say the other piece is that
even on AI review, I don't think that
we're we've really seen what the, you
know, what the best modality here is.
Like, you know, for for AI code
generation, you know, you've seen
several, you know, several very quick
iterations on what that modality is.
Like you went from C-Pilot which just
had you just had like autocomplete to
you know cursor tab to cursor agent mode
to now like moving entirely away from
interfaces that focus on the code and
moving towards like just the prompt with
cloud code and now we're seeing
background agents. So, you know, the the
way that you interact with these tools
is evolving so rapidly. And I think I
think like the the bot that comments on
GitHub to me is is just the copilot
autocomplete v1 and there's still like
several iterations of what AI code
review looks like. And uh you know, I
think the there there's something nice
about it and that like it meets it meets
users where they are. I think it is the
right logical starting point here. But I
I think it's still so early in terms of
of pushing you pushing the boundaries of
what of like what this review experience
should look like in in an Aative world.
And um that's part of why we with with
bringing the graphite agent chat into
the pull request page. Like I think that
is that is our you know our our belief
of like what does the next step here
look like? you know, can it be, you
know, not just a static reviewer that's
like, you know, asynchronously leaving
comments, but rather like a real
companion that you're building with
that's like helping you helping you get
the PR ready and like iterate on it live
um from the PR page. And I think that's
why a lot of customers are really
excited about it. That's why we're, you
know, we were we're really um you know,
thrilled to to get that out.
>> So, in this context now, you can
interact with uh with the LLMs through
graphite. you can interact with the
graphite agent to edit the code within
the PR. Uh, and you've sort of seen uh a
bunch of know Claude and others
introduce maybe review elements and
you're you're kind of encroaching uh
into into that space. I guess how do you
how do you see this playing out uh with
all the caveats and as you described you
know this is all uh it's all theory
because we don't really know but still
how do you see the boundaries or the
right scope of a product? Does it need
to be a single product that does kind of
the whole agentic perspective like is it
eventually someone's using graphite they
will be using that for sort of their end
toend development and cloud code or a
devon or such will not be part of their
flow uh or do you think there's a
specific slice a specific realm of
responsibility that you think will be
will be distinct because it it
definitely feels like a massive blurring
of the lines. Yeah, I think it is. It's
rapidly. One thing I'll say is like it's
very hard to know where where this will
go and also like part of this is what
>> yeah the next week it it does it feels
like it changes it does change on like a
weekly basis but um it is also an
interesting I think we've seen we've
seen like diff different levels of
interest from the base model providers
of I think at one point it looked like
you know Anthropic was going to focus
entirely on on just code generation and
open AI was going to go full consumer
and now you know open AI has kind of
gone back the the direction and said
like no we actually want to own
everything which is that which is like
you know kind of cool and and like
ambitious of of them to to go that
direction. But I think there is this
this question of like to what extent do
the base model providers like remain
base model providers or do they you know
do they continue to go you to go like
upstack and and own more of the
application layer. Um my my belief there
is that they at least at least so far um
you know they they mostly want to they
only own applications in so far as it it
feeds back training data to them. So I
think that's the that's kind of the
logical you know boundary for for some
of those company base models is like
what what is like the the minimum scope
needed to to get good training data back
so they can RL. So um I think for for us
u our view is that we'll likely have a
lot of competition among among who is
generating the code even who is
providing like the review agents. I
could see a world where graphite isn't
necessarily like building a firstparty
review agent if if others get good
enough. Like um our our goal is very
much to be you know to be like the
interface layer and um the place where
like the best place to interact with and
control you know many different agents
on you know working on your your code
changes. So u you know we think the
winning platform I think there will be
opportunities to build the best-in-class
you know agents for each task in in the
software development life cycle. I also
think then there's another opportunity
to be the control plane for all of those
agents and that is really where where I
think we you know we see the the most
opportunity in some of these cases like
with AI review I think you have to build
the agent because there just aren't
there aren't good opportunity like
aren't good alternatives out there but
like as you you know for instance we we
don't really there's a ton of companies
doing like background agents for code
generation we're not super interested in
getting into you know building like a
graphite like codegen agent like we
would much rather be you know be like
the place where you know you prompt you
prompt your agents um they go off create
PRs for you hand you back you review
them in graphite you merge them in
graphite like that entire create review
merge process um all happens from you
know from our control plane
>> I'm interpreting what you're saying as
as more of the user experience and you
know maybe that sort of core element of
>> of what you started graphite with is
where you where you feel there's an
opportunity to kind of orchestrate this
activity
>> um but and I I guess to to to challenge
like stepping out of that a little bit.
Uh it it feels to me and feel free to
sort of you know call me an idiot on
this but uh that um that like the
stacked PRs for instance that you
started with uh in in in sort of the
human review or reality were very still
are very necessary because you're
working on something big and you publish
this sort of piece of work so that
humans can review it. Um, if AI is doing
the review, I think I would want to
consume that review as part of my
ongoing development as opposed to wait
until I publish a PR. Maybe it even like
reduces the value of that stacked PR uh
because the AI is already reviewing it
over uh as I build. Uh but but even even
for that first bit like why when you
have review and and the review is done
by AI, why do I need to wait until I
open the pull request, why is that point
in time
needed for the AI review. I get why it's
needed for the human review, but why why
for the AI review?
>> We're going to jump into the second half
of our conversation, but first, a quick
shout out to AI Native DevCon. Two days
of hands-on sessions, deep dives, and
honest conversations about what it means
to build AI native software. November
18th and 19th in New York, or join
virtually from anywhere. Tickets and
details at a native.io/devcon.
See you there.
>> I'd say a couple things. Like one I I
would challenge the assumption that
stack PRs are less valuable in a world
where AI is generating the code because
I think if anything what we've seen is
that uh especially for for like
background agents if you just kind of
let them run wild the result is you get
you know multi,000line you know
unintelligible PRs and uh you certainly
there's something there are things that
we can do on the PR interface itself to
to like guide you through the change and
help you understand it. Um, but I think
fundamentally, especially as you're as
you're building with with multiple
agents or as you're having these agents
do longer, you know, autonomous tracks
of of work. Uh, I I think that it is
really it will be increasingly important
to have those changes be understandable
and digestible by, you know, by the
humans that that need to check it. So,
um, we've built we built the graphite
MCP. uh we have like we have a lot of
our a lot of our our customers are now
using actually having their agents
create stack PRs uh precisely because it
makes them easier to review on the other
side. Yeah, that's actually super
interesting and and I can totally relate
which is uh the agents when they do a
long work. If you think of stackr is a
way for you to continue working while
you are submitting stuff to review is
kind of the core of it actually these
sort of agents are a great example of
that because they don't want to wait and
you want to be able to review their work
incrementally and and I guess probably
there will be interfaces of once they
did submit something if there was
substantial correction in the review
they might kind of revert back to that
point and continue the work from there
uh which is something that humans will
probably be quite uh annoyed uh at doing
>> exactly Exactly. And I think the the
revertability piece is another good
point there of like having you know
having like you know smaller you know
smaller pieces and and like a clear
history I think enables you to like more
easily figure out like where was what
was the change that that introduced this
problem like lets you roll back more
precisely like there's a lot of benefits
there to you know to having your agents
work in in smaller pieces and stacking
like a fantastic workflow uh to to
enable them to do that. Uh the second
point that I I wanted to make though was
that I I think a lot of folks like
really uh kind of get stuck on the idea
of like code review being the only value
of code review being this validation
step. And I think that that's that's
certainly you know one of the main
benefits of it. But I think the the
other piece, you know, the other two
pieces I'd say that are often missed of
this is that uh I think code review is
is also a great is also super important
in like sharing like sharing knowledge
across the team of uh helping you know
helping other engineers understand like
what is you know what is actually you
know going out to production what is
changing. Uh it's also a great moment of
teaching where you know where you f you
get a lot of feedback and um you you're
able to you're able to like improve u
the way that you're approaching
approaching your projects. So um those
two you know certainly the there's like
the validation quality piece u I think
AI can can take on but I think the the
latter two um are actually you know more
important than ever in many ways because
you know you have now if if even the
engineer who's like authoring the PR
doesn't fully understand the change like
you know I think there's it's all the
more important that you have you have a
moment to where you know where you know
you walk through everything and um you
can clearly communicate like what is
changing in the codebase
Similarly, I think having you know
sharing that with others uh you know
teaching others like what is what is
good about this change and what is not
uh like what what learnings they want to
apply and um and also having a moment
then to like feed any any like systemic
things back into uh into the the
reviewer and give it more more rules for
the future of what it should or
shouldn't look at like that piece is is
really important. So I think that those
you certainly the validation you know
code the purpose of code review I think
will shift over of human review at least
like will will shift from validation you
know more to the the like you know
pedagogy and and you know knowledge
sharing pieces. But I I do think that
those you know those two are
fundamentally you know I think arguably
more important in in terms of like why
we do code review today than than the
validation pieces anyways.
>> Yeah. Interesting. So I guess you're
you're describing a a reality in which
maybe the um I guess the code review
that is fully automated. You might
eventually want to consume that as a
natural part of the of the agentic
development. It's a it's a it's a point
in time in which it is done in a
different system and needs to come back
to you. That's a that's maybe a hiccup.
Maybe they call into graphite through
that MCP not just to open the poll
request but to actually run the review
and kind of get the results. Um but but
then the I guess you mentioned two
things that are maybe long-term
relevant. One is the notion of a stacked
PR even if it is whether it is or isn't
reviewed incrementally just as a as a as
a means of demarcation of different
points in time. And second is uh as a
means of review of work that's been done
to be able to get guidance uh and to
provide guidance uh on what's there sort
of learn and guide uh the AI. I guess in
that context you probably would at some
point would have to veer away from
reviewing the code and reviewing some
analysis of the code, right? Because
it's just a it's a it's an unpleasant uh
uh future to imagine one in which all we
do is is uh is read code uh and uh and
review and kind of comment and nitpick
on it. Does that sound about right? Like
you're going to need some summaries or
sort of a uh reviews of the changes. Is
that is that a likely future? Yeah, I I
mean I think the the framework that that
we talk about internally here is that uh
I think we we see three steps in in the
process and like the evolution of of
engineering and and code review as a
product of that. like the first the
first step uh which I think we're we're
somewhat moving past already is is one
where you know the IC engineer is
primarily the one like writing the code
or generating it with tab complete um
and then review is is very much like a
process of of looking at every single
line of code like really carefully
inspecting it. I think phase the second
phase that we're now you know we're now
entering or have entered is one where
the job of engineering feels more like
you know an engineering manager where
you know you're you're working with and
orchestrating uh like a team of agents
that are going and building they're
handing you back changes you're you know
you're reviewing you're certainly
reviewing the code but a lot of it is is
like reviewing the you know the design
docs and the architecture and kind of
the higher level points um still being
able to introspect into the code But uh
you know but a lot of that is happening
of the review and like what you're
looking for is happening at a higher
level of abstraction. Uh the the details
there are starting to be handled more by
AI review in in that world. And then um
I'd say the third uh the third level
which we have not gotten to yet. Um but
we'll you know I think we will start to
see if if everything gets uh you know if
everything gets gets good enough is uh
uh one where I'd say that you it almost
looks more like work what working with
an external dev agency would be where
you're giving just highle specs u and
then you're getting back like the
artifact of the finished product and um
you're reviewing that versus you may not
even ever necessarily look at the the
underlying code or or need to understand
it but um you're you're primarily
reviewing like the whatever that
finished product is and I think we're
you know we're somewhere between like
phases one and two right now and then I
think uh in in the coming years we have
the opportunity to jump from two to
three.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And clearly we're sort of
quite aligned in terms of the sort of
spectriven uh uh development.
>> Yeah. You guys you guys think about this
so a lot.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's about that. I guess the
the um uh the question here would be uh
uh review is an after the fact uh um
kind of reality right you're looking at
the output and you're saying well is the
output of uh proper and and to an extent
the more you've defined up front the
less you need to to review or at least
the review becomes a bit more
straightforward which is uh uh did you
did you adhere uh to uh to the to the
specification and and so I think that's
a future I agree that it's a it's a
journey you know and uh and at the
moment it's it's there and to an extent
my question about
um uh what is the source of truth is is
a bit about that right it is about you
know where where are the what's the spec
assisted review uh that you have there
to tell you what's correct you know
whether it's a cloud MD or a style guide
uh and I think it's interesting to think
about how that gets managed as well
within an organization
>> yeah I think that there's there's a lot
there in terms of of connecting back to
what I was saying earlier around around
like How do we start to show the like
the chat history or like the prompts,
the agent logs like in in the pull
request? How do we pull in the right the
right provenence and context around like
where was the spec like where was the
Figma design file? Uh what was the what
was like the intention of this change
and capturing that more completely than
I think just a PR description today, you
know, today just isn't sufficient
anymore. Um, if if we want agents to be
able to do like a really high quality
review, even even for humans, I think
that there is there is like that level
of of subjectivity about review today
that um, you know, would really benefit
from having, you know, having more
context and um, you know, I think I I'm
curious, you know, I'd be curious to
hear a little bit more about how you
think about it of like how do you kind
of more most completely capture the the
spec of like what was the intention of a
change and u, and then turn add into
something that that can then be, you
know, be digestible by by an either an a
reviewer or a human on the other side of
that.
>> Yeah. I mean, I think uh so, you know,
clearly kind of flipping roles here a
little bit on it, but yeah, clearly uh
um clearly there's an evolution there to
sort of think about, you know, how do
you create a spec, how do you read it,
what does a spec even contain? Um you
you referred now to sort of the spec of
a change of going from state A to state
B. We think a lot as well about long
lived specs, not just the task at hand,
but rather uh some document that
captures uh some long lived definition
of either what you're building or how
you want to build and then how do you
adhere to that. Uh one thing that's sort
of quite interesting and that was I
don't know if you've encountered it.
Well, I guess in your case, you're
running your own agent, so you're fine.
But because we connect to different
agents, we find that the same uh
guidance that you want to provide uh
would get very different adherence. You
know, you might have one
state-of-the-art agent, you know, take
some instruction and follow it 80% of
the time and another follow it 30% of
the time. And it might just be a wording
difference. Sonic 45 requires very
different prompting than four as was the
five and when it came out versus the
predecessors. Um, and so so I think the
notion of how do you manage this
knowledge uh and uh and the social truth
is uh is interesting and we need
visibility, we need observability, you
know, which which I guess again it comes
back, you know, for us I'm a bit of a
broken record there. we take about talk
about spectriven development as a new
development paradigm over time but the
transition period is an interesting one
uh as it's still still quite impactful
um and I think I think review is at a
clearly very important place there and
we need to see
uh what is being reviewed like there
would always be a need to review but
what is being reviewed
I want to uh shift to talk a little bit
about the the business and the kind of
the uh startup side maybe of uh of the
company want to close off on some
futures. Um so uh a common debate today
in sort of startup land on specifically
in developer land is just the pricing
model right you are yeah today uh I I
believe you're sort of still a sort of a
seatbased primarily how many developers
are using this which makes sense you're
collaborating on it uh
>> you're going to have a lot of AI workers
I don't know if they're going to
purchase a seat I guess how do you think
about what's the right long-term uh kind
of value attribution right or pricing
model uh for for products like uh like
yours.
>> Yeah, there's certainly a big shift
happening right now and across across
industries on collaborative tooling
where historically it made sense to
price per seat. I think we're we're
still I think that is still like what
largely what buyers are anchored to and
uh we've been we've certainly been
exploring like what would a usage based
model look like you know if we if we
charge by you know by PR volume or um by
you know PR's review yeah PR's reviewed
like lines of code something there
different like parameters we could we
could use there but um I I think the
challenge the challenge there is like
what is the right time to what's the
right time to innovate and is is pricing
the thing that we want to spend our our
innovation points on and and if so like
when you know do we want to lead do we
want to like lead the market in in doing
that and uh I think that the I think
that for now certainly you know proceed
is still very much the model you know
the the paradigm that we're operating in
uh I I see over the next year uh
especially as as teams start to you as
as companies start to to like you know
change the way that they think about
scaling their teams and you know maybe
not hire as as many engineers as they
scale and shift more towards towards
like relying on on background agents for
those work those workloads. U the type
of thing that would make us like more
seriously consider moving over to to
usage base. I I think that will be the
end state here. It's more a matter of
like when is the right time to pull that
lever.
>> Yeah, I do think that it's super
interesting to see how uh how things
play out. Um I at uh on with a sneak hat
on um thinking about sort of security at
similar we we secure the work of
developers and so the more developers
you have contributing the more uh the
more it makes sense to charge and when
you think about outcomebased pricing and
a lot of that sort of aspiration in this
world you can say well fine maybe we do
you know for every vulnerability fixed
but then you get into the conversation
of like what's a vulnerability and was
it vulnerable no what's an extreme uh so
it gets very hairy I think uh I I think
there's a world of learning there. If
you switch to utility based pricing and
you charge by scan, you are potentially
incentivizing the wrong behavior uh
because people want to scan less. Um I
imagine there will be there will be some
sort of similarity of like the number of
reviews is a is a tricky proposition for
you. Right.
>> Right. I think there's there kind of two
competing competing factors there. Like
on the one hand, as you say, we don't
want to disincentivize the thing that we
we believe our our users should be doing
more of. like we want users to create
more PRs. We want them to stack. Like we
don't want that to be, you know, we
don't want you to feel like, oh, you're
you're now paying more because you're
doing the thing that graphite told you
to do. Uh at the same time though I
think that there's you know it uh I mean
goal Roger one of our investors um and
and you know a great product mentor of
mine from the square days u he has like
a great blog post on this of like how
how Google thought about like charging
you know why they charge for impressions
and not for you know conversions or
clickthroughs even and that being you
know because the like you want to charge
for things that are under your control
as you know as the business like you
know, if somebody makes shitty ad copy,
you know, it's not on Google. It's not
on Google whether or not you actually
like click through to the you to the
site or not. Like Google's job is just
to show you is to like serve you the ad
in the first place. And I think about a
similar thing here where you know even
like completion it's like what what is
the definition of completion? Like if
you expose yourself to too much
subjectivity on on and and variability
on the user input side like then all of
a sudden your you know your pricing is
it just becomes like you know really
hard to model hard to you know hard to
reason about and like hard to really
rely on versus like keeping it as as
something that's like fundamentally
under your control. I find it a little
bit funny how uh so many things get
emphasized with AI and one of them is
the measure of developer productivity
because really what you want is you want
to say hey I'm going to charge by the
amount of productivity I've uh provided
to you if only if only we could measure
what that uh what that actually means.
Um so um Mel thanks for all the great
insights. I want to uh finish off with
just a bit of of futures of it. Uh so
for starters you you touched on this a
little bit but uh what is it that you
think is the role of uh of a developer
in the future? I'm talking about someone
who does it for a living if you think
that exists if you try to cast your eyes
far like five years or like maybe even
10. What do you what do you think is uh
is the role of a of a developer? What
does it look like? It really is like
becomes one of defining like at a high
level like what you know what the the
experience should be you know to some
extent like what are you what are like
the technologies that should be used
like what are the the problems like the
hard problems that need to be solved and
then like working I think it is working
collaboratively with with agents to you
know to go ahead and find to find the
best solution to them to iterate on that
um and to you know then to like get that
out to to your end customers and um that
it looks more I think it does it does
look like more like review or more like
uh you know you're operating at a higher
level of abstraction than likely than
than code today. Uh but I still think
that you need to be able to you'll need
to be able to like dive deep into the
code in some cases then u know kind of
what approaches to use at at the right
time. Some of that will be like the
agents will be informing you of this.
Sometimes you'll be informing them like
much like a collaborative team works
today like you know not everyone will
have you not everyone on your team you
know knows everything or has has the
right answer to every problem but you
know together with you know with your
human and and agent colleagues you'll
figure out the the right solution. I
guess just to sort of poke on that a
little bit, the if you if you spend most
of your time at a higher level, like
would you not lose or maybe in some
cases never acquire the skills to be
able to review the code? I mean, don't
we need to kind of find a way to not
have that kind of uncanny valley, you
know, like it can nearly code but not
quite uh and solve that with other
tools?
>> I think this is this is like the great
debate, right? because I think you know
a lot of us don't really understand like
a lot of like don't have to understand
like compilers today or like you know
you don't you don't need to like get
down to you know be able to look at at
like machine code and and understand
yeah there there's like there there are
we have like jumped up levels of
abstraction before successfully
difference there is that those are you
more deterministic like far more
deterministic than what we're dealing
with now but um I do think that there is
you have been able to to navigate those
changes in the past. I I still think
that there is a you know there is like
fundamentally a reason why we learn
those things and even if we don't then
use them in you know in our day-to-day
as as engineers like I think that there
is there is value in in learning that
and that's you know certainly something
that that I I'm curious to see the the
result of you know every every like CS
graduate having access to cursor now you
know versus versus a few years ago like
I think there's a you know there's a
bullcase there of like it makes everyone
you know far more productive and able to
like learn faster and build things
faster and get more excited about about
the the field. Uh I also think that
there is a there's potentially a
challenge coming of like you know not of
like a whole a whole class of like
newrad engineers like not necessarily
having u you know having the skills uh
and knowledge that they need to like be
able to to jump down into you jump down
a layer of abstraction anymore.
>> Yeah. And that that's actually precisely
sort of the uh the last question I had
for you, which is if you had an
18-year-old child uh right now and they
were considering whether or not to go
into a CS degree in university, would
you recommend they do or they don't?
>> I still think I I would I would just say
that there there basically two there
basically two angles that I'd say you
should go. It's either you know either
you go super deep on it and say you know
you want to become an expert in you know
in like a deep deep technology you know
something that just requires that will
take a long time um for for AI to and
require a lot of specialized knowledge
will take a long time for AI to to catch
up to uh or the other side of it is like
go go wide and develop you know develop
you know design skills develop like uh
then develop like business skills and
product and um you have have like a a
breadth of you know of influences and u
you know of of abilities there such that
you can better you know better inform
the agent of what to build and um that
piece I think you know we're seeing we
talk about like does like product and
design and edge kind of all all merge
together in in some not so distant
future like I think that is there is
some world where the the role of
engineers is either you know it's either
going to get like much broader in in
some cases and like much deeper in
others but the the in between of like
you know just kind of existing in the
the scope that that we have before I
think is not going to last very long.
>> I love the perspective like to sort of
pick your pick your battle but the the
t-shirt might a little bit tricky uh in
this world.
>> Um thanks uh thanks a lot for all the
great insights and good luck uh
reviewing uh and kind of evolving review
uh with graphite.
>> Thank you. I really enjoyed this. Thanks
for having me, Guy.
>> And thanks everybody for tuning in. And
I hope you join us for the next one.